<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://Francois3344.github.io</id>
    <title>Sophia</title>
    <updated>2024-09-14T02:49:35.551Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://Francois3344.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://Francois3344.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Because it&apos;s there.</subtitle>
    <logo>https://Francois3344.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://Francois3344.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2024, Sophia</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lonely baby shark]]></title>
        <id>https://Francois3344.github.io/post/lonely-baby-shark/</id>
        <link href="https://Francois3344.github.io/post/lonely-baby-shark/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-09-14T02:46:48.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>你为什么悲伤，<br>
我亲爱的小鲨鱼。<br>
你在海里吐泡泡，<br>
忧伤眼眸望着天。<br>
太阳踽踽向西行，<br>
浮光碎金尽染波。</p>
<p>Why are you sad, my lovely baby shark<br>
you’re bubbling in the sea<br>
lonely eyes staring the sky<br>
It travels to the west,<br>
golden light dyes the wave.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transcendentalism]]></title>
        <id>https://Francois3344.github.io/post/transcendentalism/</id>
        <link href="https://Francois3344.github.io/post/transcendentalism/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-09-12T00:32:26.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>无人知晓路径通向何方<br>
no one knows where it is to lead<br>
追寻的祂只留下圣光<br>
the HE followed left only HE the he<br>
扭曲的形体和光芒<br>
screwy shapes and light<br>
我在黑暗中踽踽独行<br>
I step and step around in the dark</p>
<p>信此值永生<br>
believe in HE and get eternity<br>
破旧教堂的彩窗如是说<br>
said you the colorful windows in church<br>
你站在高台之上<br>
you are high in heaven<br>
我找寻你不可求亦不可达的终点<br>
I am looking for the fading hidden you in  universe</p>
<p>乌鸦叫嚷着切切救赎的谎言<br>
crows fill the world with saving lies<br>
林立的高楼大厦遮迷懦弱者眼眸<br>
they lose eyes in the standing buildings<br>
随着人群徒劳向天空伸出找寻的双手<br>
asking for saving with crowds from sky<br>
除了尘埃满身什么也无<br>
get nothing without dust overall</p>
<p>我向上帝打去由他付费的电话<br>
I made a call collected to God<br>
我并不在乎<br>
I don't care any more</p>
<p>这里不是伊甸<br>
but there is never Eden in it<br>
你将去往何方<br>
where you are going and being<br>
我的救赎<br>
my salvation of soul</p>
<p>Slip inside the eye of your mind<br>
Don't you know you might find<br>
A better place to play<br>
You said that you'd never been<br>
But all the things that you've seen<br>
Slowly fade away</p>
<p>So I start a revelation from my bed<br>
'Cause you said the brains I had went to my head<br>
no one knows where it’s to lead<br>
the HE followed left only HE the he<br>
screwy shapes and light<br>
I wander and wander around in the dark</p>
<p>believe in HE and get eternity<br>
said the colorful windows in church<br>
you are high in heaven<br>
I am looking for the fading /hidden you in universe<br>
but I can’t find</p>
<p>Take me to the place where you go<br>
Where nobody knows<br>
If it's night or day<br>
but there is never Eden in it<br>
where you are going and being<br>
my salvation of soul</p>
<p>I’m gonna start a revelation from my bed<br>
'Cause you said the brains I had went to my head<br>
crows fill the world with salvation lies<br>
they lose eyes in the standing buildings<br>
asking for saving with crowds from sky<br>
get nothing only dust overall</p>
<p>believe in HE and get eternity<br>
said the colorful windows in church<br>
you are high in heaven<br>
I am looking for the fading /hidden you in universe<br>
but I can’t find</p>
<p>believe in HE and get eternity<br>
said the decayed gates in church<br>
you are now in hell<br>
I am looking for the fading /hidden you in universe<br>
but I can’t find</p>
<p>believe in HE and get eternity<br>
said the messy messy in church<br>
you are in nowhere<br>
I am looking for the fading /hidden you here<br>
I called collect to God<br>
I called collect to God<br>
I don’t care<br>
I’ve found it.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HAPPY]]></title>
        <id>https://Francois3344.github.io/post/happy/</id>
        <link href="https://Francois3344.github.io/post/happy/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-09-12T00:31:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was trapped in wordy labyrinth,<br>
back and forth,<br>
with words on the wall,<br>
with emotions in the beam.</p>
<p>They tell me to be happy, as the words on the wall said,<br>
though I saw only meaningless signals.<br>
WHY?</p>
<p>H-A-P-P-Y---<br>
means happy, happy itself.<br>
They said, how can you use happy for sadness?<br>
You’ve mistaken the meaning.</p>
<p>Happy should be happy,<br>
but it can also be sad.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dare to die]]></title>
        <id>https://Francois3344.github.io/post/dare-to-die/</id>
        <link href="https://Francois3344.github.io/post/dare-to-die/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-09-12T00:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Boring games, to which naive eyes are attracted<br>
Nobody knows where the train is from or to.<br>
This is, God says, what you are determined to do<br>
You are determined to,<br>
like a fawn to death,<br>
like a moth to flame.</p>
<p>Passengers are laughing, shouting, celebrating:<br>
FOR DAYS WE HAVE AND DAYS WE LOST !<br>
FOR PAST DEATH AND FUTURE DEATH !<br>
Rubbish on the floor,<br>
Graffiti on the door,<br>
for crazy days<br>
for shiny nights.</p>
<p>“ Forest! ”<br>
Smog --- the escaping souls<br>
Wind --- are smashed into dust<br>
Sunset --- ninety nine rise and fall of dying sun,<br>
Destruction!</p>
<p>“Sea!”<br>
Waves --- angels’ arms hold the necks down<br>
Boats --- childish songs take everything back<br>
Beacon --- ninety nine up and down of light,<br>
Wax and Wane!</p>
<p>“Mountain!”<br>
Clouds --- touch edge of heaven<br>
Cliff --- step on knife of earth<br>
Rivers --- ninety nine out and fill of water,<br>
Regeneration!</p>
<p>Boring games, to which naive eyes are attracted<br>
Nobody knows where the train is from or to.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waiting]]></title>
        <id>https://Francois3344.github.io/post/waiting/</id>
        <link href="https://Francois3344.github.io/post/waiting/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-09-12T00:28:03.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I stand at the hallway, waiting<br>
I don’t know what the season is<br>
I don’t know what the weather is<br>
I don't know who I’m waiting for.</p>
<p>Tweet, tweet.<br>
It whispers, why are you here and why are you waiting?<br>
Who are you waiting for?<br>
The boy caught your heart or the girl made you’n love?</p>
<p>No, I reply, teasing its feather<br>
I don’t know who I’m waiting for<br>
I’m not for him’cause I have my rose<br>
I’m not for her’cause I have my fleur de lis.</p>
<p>Meow, meow.<br>
It murmurs, why are you here and why are you waiting?<br>
Who are you waiting for?<br>
The dream in your night or the bubbles in your life?</p>
<p>No, I reply, fondling its fur<br>
I don’t know who I’m waiting for<br>
I’m not for it’cause it never back<br>
I’m not for it’cause it’s always fake</p>
<p>Rustle, rustle.<br>
It susurrates, why are you here and why are you waiting?<br>
Who are you waiting for?<br>
The Utopia in your mind or the Eden in your heart?</p>
<p>No, I reply, appeasing its spine<br>
I don’t know who I’m waiting for<br>
I’m not for it’cause it’s broken<br>
I’m not for it’cause it’s poison</p>
<p>I step outside and see<br>
All the transparent world under eye,<br>
All the transparent world under mine,<br>
Under the firmament I’ve lost.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tragedy and Criticism]]></title>
        <id>https://Francois3344.github.io/post/tragedy-and-criticism/</id>
        <link href="https://Francois3344.github.io/post/tragedy-and-criticism/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-09-12T00:25:49.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love the books of both Yuhua and Luxun, but they definitely have great difference from each other. I think there are two points: the purpose and expressing ways.</p>
<p>Purposes. They are in different eras, so it’s easy to find that Lu paid more attention to the mess of the society, and he was always trying to figure them out. However, instead of critisizing, Yu are just telling us about the mess, not so radical as Lu. He uses some rhetorical device like irony, which makes others difficult to make clear his ideas. If you know about him, or the history he try to tell, then you will easily understand, but if you want to point out his polic faults in his masterpiece, you can’t.</p>
<p>Expressing ways. In Lu’s era, vernacular Chinese is just developed, and it’s quite different from what we use know. In his articles, he uses some images and description that are more common in ancient Chinese, and that will make them a little hard to understand. That’s the different in language using habit. In expressing, Yu always use the strategic that is for comedies to write tragedies. Yu is famous for his tragedies, not for how sad or miserable the characters are, but for the common hard life for people. When I read his books, I feel absurd because his tone is humorous, and he can even make some jokes in them, but the core of the stories are all sad. In Lu’s books and articles, he didn’t make all his stories sad or miserable. They are just stories and their have their specific purposes to convey.</p>
<p>Both of them can creating a feeling of absurd, but that can also be different. Absurd can be sad, irony, angry... Lu’s are most angry but Yu’s are always absurd and sad.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lines]]></title>
        <id>https://Francois3344.github.io/post/lines/</id>
        <link href="https://Francois3344.github.io/post/lines/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-09-12T00:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Under the pillow is a note saying, I’m Astrophel, and you?</p>
<p>I stand beside my bed, feeling confused. Today is Monday, and I am going to have my Math test in the afternoon, which gave me a extremely bad nightmare. I hate tests, and all the subjects. Now the sun is shining, and my sister is striking my door, which irritates me. I have no time to think about it, because it’s time for school.</p>
<p>On the school bus, I just can’t help thinking of the note.</p>
<p>The handwriting is definitely not mine. I prefer to write A in two strokes, but this A is in one stroke. Also, though I don’t want to admit, the handwriting is much better than mine. The note is so clean that if I give it to my mum, she must think I’m not her daughter.</p>
<p>My name is Astrophel, and it’s common to have a same name, but it’s not common to receive a note from a person with the same name and the note is under my pillow. I mean, it can’t be a coincidence. I always lock my door when I’m sleeping, since this can make me feel safety, so I’m sure that nobody can get into my room. I don’t think I would write a note and put it under my pillow.</p>
<p>“That’s strange!” I say to my friend May.<br>
“Yeah...But maybe you have schizo...phoria?”<br>
“It’s schizophrenia.”<br>
“OK, whatever, it is possible.”<br>
“...Fine, but why I changed my handwriting?”<br>
“Oh!” She says in a dramatic way, “that’s not you! That’s another you, another Astrophel!”</p>
<p>Her loud voice makes the teacher in front of us turn back and give us a glance. We shut up and fall into silence.</p>
<p>When I’m a little girl, I hoped for such unusual things which can only be seen in fictions everyday. However, there can’t be another Astrophel, another me, and it’s highly possible that the note is just a joke. Now the math test worries me most, I almost sleep in all the math classes, and now I still can’t figure out sine and cosine correctly. May is also bad at math, but she even doesn’t care about it.</p>
<p>In my uneasiness, the test comes. Tangent, adjacent, radian...</p>
<p>Damn it! I hate math!</p>
<p>I try my best to fill in all the blanks, but in vain. 30minutes later, I give up and begin to write on the scratch paper.</p>
<p>[I hate mathhhhhhhh!]<br>
[Ah, another 0!!]</p>
<p>Then I think back the note.</p>
<p>[Is it a joke?]</p>
<p>To my astonishment, a sentence appears on my scratch paper before I write.</p>
<p>{No, it’s not a joke.}</p>
<p>Wow, am I too sleepy?</p>
<p>[? Who are you?]<br>
{I’m Astrophel, maybe from another world.}<br>
[Really?]</p>
<p>Now I even want to stand up and tell everyone about it.</p>
<p>{I’m not so sure...Anyway, do you need help in math?]<br>
[Yeah! You can help me?]<br>
{Sure, I’m good at it.}<br>
[I love uuuuuuu!!!!!!!]<br>
{It’s an... easy test. I will write process on your paper, since I am having the same test too.}<br>
[So cooooool!!]</p>
<p>Well, she’s really good at it. A multiple choice which I should spend at least 5 minutes to solve, she only needs less than one minute.</p>
<p>[I have fallen in love with you.]<br>
{You are writing on the scratch paper.}<br>
[(´;︵;`)]</p>
<p>The bell rings. Before I turn in the paper, I write one last sentence:</p>
<p>[Can I see you again?]</p>
<p>There is no answer.</p>
<p>All the afternoon I am absent-minded. Her beautiful handwriting keep appearing in my mind. I am so absent that I don’t hear May is calling me.</p>
<p>“What’s wrong with you?”<br>
“Nothing...How is your test?”<br>
“As always, what about you?”<br>
“em, maybe just so-so.”</p>
<p>I don’t tell the truth. The secret belongs to the deepest corner of my heart. Though May is one of my best friends, I won’t tell her, or anyone of them, everything. I can’t tell who I can totally believe, so I prefer to keep something in my heart. “Astrophel” is one of them.</p>
<p>When I open my textbook, I see the familiar handwriting again.</p>
<p>{Hi, are you still here?}<br>
[Of course!]<br>
{...Do you have anything to ask me?}<br>
[So many things!!]<br>
{Please:)}<br>
[So, who are you?]<br>
{I’m Astrophel, I am you in another world.}<br>
[Another world?]<br>
{Yes, just like...two parallel lines.}<br>
[And now, they crisscross?]<br>
{Yes, two of us meet each other.}<br>
[You mean...there are many “us” in the universe?]<br>
{I’m not sure, but I think we are not in the same universe.}<br>
[Anyway, nice to meet you, Astrophel.]</p>
<p>I don’t notice my math teacher.<br>
“Maybe the young lady know the answer?”<br>
“Er......”</p>
<p>Damn it, I hate math.</p>
<p>{1/2}</p>
<p>“One over two!”<br>
“Right, but it’s necessary to listen carefully in class.”</p>
<p>[Thank u!]<br>
[I can’t love you too much!!]</p>
<p>I have never had such a good math class. When I have something do not understand, Astrophel will respond quickly to my question on the textbook. I get a totally new feeling, a good feeling.</p>
<p>[Will you go home now?]</p>
<p>After the school ends, I ask her.</p>
<p>{Yes, my sister is waiting for me at home.}<br>
[Wow, you have a sister too?]<br>
{She is an angel as well as a monster.}<br>
[Can’t agree more!]<br>
{Let’s go home now. Maybe your little monster is waiting for you too.}</p>
<p>When I get home, I can’t wait to chat with her. I finish my dinner quickly, and lock myself in my room.</p>
<p>[Hi, Are you here? I have just finished my dinner!]<br>
{I’m here.}</p>
<p>It’s strange that she is always there, like she is for me. Maybe she shares the same time table with me.</p>
<p>[Are you always here?]<br>
{Not exactly, but you can think so.}<br>
[Why?]<br>
{Do you forget? I’m another you, I share the same day with you.}<br>
[Oh, did you eat eggplant for lunch?]<br>
{Never, I never eat eggplant.}<br>
[That’s it!! We are comrades now!!]<br>
{Do you like science?}<br>
[I don’t know...maybe yes,but I’m not good at it.]<br>
{Since you love it, you can do it.}<br>
[Wow, you now are like some successful person in our textbook.]<br>
{Certainly I’m not, you can trust me, or not. I won’t force you, but you should follow what you love, follow your heart.}<br>
[What about you?]<br>
{I like what I’m doing, I love math, I love physics, I love what I love.}<br>
[You are so great, I can’t believe you are me.]<br>
{It’s 7 o’clock, I have to do my homework.}<br>
[OK...I decide to finish my math homework by myself from today.]<br>
{Wish you good luck!}<br>
[Thank you!]<br>
{Bye, thank yourself.}</p>
<p>I close the book. The moon is so bright, and I begin to imagine her. Maybe she likes reading? She has really beautiful handwriting. Dose she like badminton?</p>
<p>I finish my homework really hard. I lack some basic knowledge of them, and I have to go over my textbook repeatedly, that’s quite painful. Anyway, I’m happy, I enjoyed a tired but comfortable night, which I have never had before.</p>
<p>I don’t know when I fell asleep. When I get up, I am sleeping on math book, with a blanket on me. Under my face, Astrophel wrote:</p>
<p>{We may never meet again. Anyway, love what you love. Bye.}</p>
<p>The sun is shining, and I have to go to school. I write back:</p>
<p>[Bye, my Astrophel.]</p>
<hr>
<p>“Hey! Succeed?” A young lady says to the one who is taking off the helmet. The huge machine shines sprays bland blue light.<br>
“Yes...And now I know who talked to me when I was a young girl.”<br>
“Don’t tell me it’s yourself.”<br>
“It was me.”<br>
“How did you feel then?”<br>
“I’m thankful to myself.”</p>
<p>The sun is shining, a beam of light gets into the underground lab through the dormant window. She tries to hold the particles, but the waves just cross her hands.</p>
<p>“I am doing what I love.”</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>